American Colonization Society Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- I: Incoming Correspondence, 1819-1917 (Box I:A1-I:E5, Reel 1-181)
  - A: Domestic Letters, 1823-1912 (Box I:A1-I:A298, Reel 1-153)
    - 1857 (Box I:A146 pt. 1, Reel 81)
      - Jan. 1-Feb. 13
      - Feb. 14-Mar. 31 (Box I:A146 pt. 1, Reel 81)
      - Apr. 1-May 7 (Box I:A147 pt. 1, Reel 82)
      - May 8-June 29 (Box I:A147 pt. 2, Reel 82)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A148, Reel 82)
      - Oct. 1-Nov. 9 (Box I:A149 pt. 1, Reel 83)
      - Nov. 10-Dec. 31 (Box I:A149 pt. 2, Reel 83)
    - 1858 (Box I:A150, Reel 83)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A151, Reel 84)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A152, Reel 84)
      - Oct.1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A153, Reel 85)
    - 1859 (Box I:A154, Reel 85)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-May 9 (Box I:A155 pt. 1, Reel 86)
      - May 10-June 30 (Box I:A155 pt. 2, Reel 86)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A156, Reel 87)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A157, Reel 87)
    - 1860 (Box I:A158 pt. 1, Reel 88)
      - Jan. 1-Feb. 19
      - Feb. 20-Mar. 31 (Box I:A158 pt. 2, Reel 88)
      - Apr. 2-May 22 (Box I:A159 pt. 1, Reel 89)
      - May 23-June 30 (Box I:A159 pt. 2, Reel 89)
      - July 2-Sept. 29 (Box I:A160, Reel 89)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A161, Reel 90)
    - 1861 (Box I:A162, Reel 91)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 30
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A163, Reel 91)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A164, Reel 92)
      - Oct. 2-Dec. 31 (Box I:A165, Reel 92)
    - 1862 (Box I:A166)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A167, Reel 93)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A168, Reel 93)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A169, Reel 93)
    - 1863 (Box I:A170, Reel 94)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A171, Reel 94)
      - July 1-Sept. 29 (Box I:A172, Reel 94)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A173, Reel 95)
    - 1864 (Box I:A174, Reel 95)
      - Jan. 4-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A175, Reel 95)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A176, Reel 96)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A177, Reel 96)
    - 1865 (Box I:A178, Reel 97)
      - Jan. 3-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A179, Reel 97)
      - July 1-Sept. 29 (Box I:A180, Reel 97)
      - Oct. 2-Dec. 30 (Box I:A181, Reel 98)
    - 1866 (Box I:A182, Reel 98)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 30
      - Apr. 2-June 30 (Box I:A183, Reel 98)
      - July 1-Sept. 29 (Box I:A184, Reel 99)
      - Oct. 1-Nov. 4 (Box I:A185 pt.1, Reel 99)
      - Nov. 5-Dec. 31 (Box I:A185 pt.12, Reel 99)
    - 1867 (Box I:A186, Reel 100)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A187, Reel 100)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A188, Reel 100)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A189, Reel 101)
    - 1868 (Box I:A190 pt. 1, Reel 101)
      - Jan. 1-Feb. 25
      - Feb. 26-Mar. 31 (Box I:A190 pt. 2, Reel 101)
      - Apr. 1-27 (Box I:A191 pt. 1, Reel 102)
      - Apr. 28-June 30 (Box I:A191 pt. 2, Reel 102)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A192, Reel 102)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A193, Reel 103)
    - 1869 (Box I:A194, Reel 103)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A195, Reel 104)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A196, Reel 104)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 30 (Box I:A197, Reel 105)
    - 1870 (Box I:A198, Reel 105)
      - Jan. 2-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A199, Reel 106)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A200, Reel 106)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A201, Reel 107)
    - 1871 (Box I:A202, Reel 107)
      - Jan. 2-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A203, Reel 108)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A204, Reel 108)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 30 (Box I:A205, Reel 109)
    - 1872 (Box I:A206, Reel 109)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 30
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A207, Reel 110)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A208, Reel 110)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A209, Reel 110)
    - 1873 (Box I:A210, Reel 111)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A211, Reel 111)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A212, Reel 111)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A213, Reel 112)
    - 1874
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31 (Box I:A214, Reel 112)
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A215, Reel 112)
      - July 2-Sept. 30 (Box I:A216, Reel 113)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A217, Reel 113)
    - 1875 (Box I:A218, Reel 113)
      - Jan. 2-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A219, Reel 114)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A220, Reel 114)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A221, Reel 114)
    - 1876 (Box I:A222, Reel 114)
      - Jan. 3-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A223, Reel 115)
      - July 1-Sept. 29 (Box I:A224, Reel 115)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 30 (Box I:A225, Reel 115)
    - 1877 (Box I:A226, Reel 115)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A227, Reel 116A)
      - July 2-Sept. 30 (Box I:A228, Reel 116A)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A229, Reel 116B)
    - 1878 (Box I:A230, Reel 117)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A231, Reel 117)
      - July 1-Sept. 31 (Box I:A232, Reel 117)
      - Oct. 4-Dec. 31 (Box I:A233, Reel 118)
    - 1879 (Box I:A234, Reel 118)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A235, Reel 118)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A236, Reel 119)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A237, Reel 119)
    - 1880 (Box I:A238, Reel 120)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A239, Reel 120)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A240, Reel 120)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A241, Reel 121)
    - 1881 (Box I:A242, Reel 121)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 29 (Box I:A243, Reel 121)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A244, Reel 122)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 30 (Box I:A245, Reel 122)
    - 1882 (Box I:A246, Reel 122)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A247, Reel 123)
      - July 1-Sept. 29 (Box I:A248, Reel 123)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A249, Reel 123)
    - 1883 (Box I:A250, Reel 124)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A251, Reel 124)
      - July 2-Sept. 30 (Box I:A252, Reel 124)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A253, Reel 125)
    - 1884 (Box I:A254, Reel 125)
      - Jan. 2-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A255, Reel 125)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A256, Reel 126)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A257, Reel 126)
    - 1885 (Box I:A258, Reel 126)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 2-June 29 (Box I:A259, Reel 127)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A260, Reel 127)
      - Oct. 2-Dec. 31 (Box I:A261, Reel 127)
    - 1886 (Box I:A262, Reel 128)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A263, Reel 128)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A264, Reel 128)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A265, Reel 129)
    - 1887 (Box I:A266, Reel 129)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A267, Reel 130)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A268, Reel 130)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A269, Reel 130)
    - 1888 (Box I:A270, Reel 131)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 31
      - Apr. 1-June 30 (Box I:A271, Reel 131)
      - July 1-Sept. 30 (Box I:A272, Reel 131)
      - Oct. 1-Dec. 31 (Box I:A273, Reel 132)
    - 1889 (Box I:A274, Reel 132)
      - Jan.-Mar., (13 folders)
      - Apr.-June, (11 folders)
      - July-Sept., (10 folders) (Box I:A275, Reel 133)
      - Oct.-Dec., (12 folders)
    - 1890 (Box I:A276, Reel 133-134)
      - Jan.-Mar., (15 folders)
      - Apr.-June
        - Index and nos. 1-25, (6 folders)
        - Nos. 126-374, (10 folders) (Box I:A277, Reel 134)
      - July-Sept.
        - Index and nos. 1-200, (9 folders)
        - Nos. 201-277, (3 folders) (Box I:A278, Reel 135)
      - Oct.-Dec.
        - Index and nos. 1-400, (17 folders)
        - Nos. 401-437, (2 folders) (Box I:A279, Reel 136)
    - 1891
      - Jan.-Mar., (19 folders)
      - Apr. -June, (18 folders) (Box I:A280, Reel 137)
      - July, (6 folders)
      - Aug.-Sept., (14 folders) (Box I:A281, Reel 138)
      - Oct., (7 folders)
      - Nov.-Dec., (16 folders) (Box I:A282, Reel 139)
    - 1892
      - Special letters
      - Index and nos. 1-150, (7 folders)
      - Nos. 151-284, (5 folders) (Box I:A283, Reel 140)
      - Mar.-June, (14 folders)
      - June-Dec., (16 folders) (Box I:A284, Reel 141)
    - 1893, Jan.-1894, Jan.
      - Index and nos. 1-200
      - Nos. 201-382, (7 folders) (Box I:A285, Reel 142)
    - 1892, Nov.-1894, July, (15 folders)
    - 1894, July-Dec., (14 folders) (Box I:A286, Reel 143)
    - 1894, Dec.-1895, June
      - Index and nos. 1-150, (7 folders)
      - Nos. 151-387, (9 folders) (Box I:A287, Reel 144)
      - Index and nos. 1-300, (13 folders)
      - Nos. 301-500, (4 folders) (Box I:A288, Reel 145)
    - 1894-1896, Feb.
      - Index and nos. 1-450, (19 folders)
      - Nos. 451- 610, (7 folders) (Box I:A289, Reel 146)
    - 1896, Feb.-1897, Apr.
      - Index and nos. 1-400, (17 folders)
      - Nos. 401-662, (11 folders) (Box I:A290, Reel 147)
    - 1897, Apr.-1899, Mar. and 1893-1897
      - Index and nos. 1-200, (9 folders)
      - Nos. 201-381, (7 folders) (Box I:A291, Reel 148)
    - 1899, Mar.-1903, May, (17 folders)
    - 1899, Mar.-1903, May, (17 folders) (Box I:A292, Reel 149)
    - 1902, May-1906, June
      - Index and nos. 1-150, (7 folders)
      - Nos. 151-384, (9 folders) (Box I:A293, Reel 150)
    - 1904, Mar.-1906, June
      - Index and nos. 1-250, (11 folders)
      - Nos. 251-364, (4 folders) (Box I:A294, Reel 151)
    - 1906, July-1908, July, (16 folders)
    - 1908, July-1912, Mar., (16 folders) (Box I:A295, Reel 152)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1911-1912, (2 folders)
    - Register of incoming letters (1816-1823) (Box I:A296, Reel 153)
    - Index to letters received (1839-1855) (Box I:A297, Reel 153)
    - Incoming letter register (1863) (Box I:A298, Reel 153)
  - B: Letters from Liberia, 1833-1917 (Box I:B1-I:B32, Reel 153-173)
    Letters received by the society from colonists and society and colony officials in Liberia.
    Letters from Liberia before 1833 are interfiled in Series I-A. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1833, Feb. 1-1836, Dec. 18 (Box I:B1, Reel 153)
    - 1839, Nov. 12-1842, June 20 (Box I:B2, Reel 154)
    - 1847, July 24-1848, Dec. 11 (Box I:B3 pt. 1, Reel 154)
    - 1848, Jan. 3-1850, May 16 (Box I:B3 pt. 2, Reel 154)
    - 1850, July 9-1851, Nov. 6 (Box I:B4, Reel 155)
    - 1851, Nov. 29-1853, Jan. 13 (Box I:B5 pt. 1, Reel 155)
    - 1853, Jan. 20-Oct. 3 (Box I:B5 pt. 2, Reel 155)
    - 1853, Jan. 29-1854, Aug. 15 (Box I:B6 pt. 1, Reel 156)
    - 1854, Aug. 16-1856, May 14 (Box I:B6 pt. 2, Reel 156)
    - 1856, May 10-1857, Apr. 2 (Box I:B7 pt. 1, Reel 157)
    - 1857, Apr. 23-Dec. 21 (Box I:B7 pt. 2, Reel 157)
    - 1858 (Box I:B8 pt. 1, Reel 158)
      - Jan. 11-July 16
      - July 17-Nov. 16 (Box I:B8 pt. 2, Reel 158)
    - 1858, Nov. 20-1859, Feb. 29 (Box I:B9 pt. 1, Reel 158)
    - 1859, Mar. 1-Nov. 16 (Box I:B9 pt. 2, Reel 159)
    - 1859, Dec. 2-1860, July 2 (Box I:B10 pt. 1, Reel 159)
    - 1860, July-Oct. 22 (Box I:B10 pt. 2, Reel 159)
    - 1860, Oct. 22-1861, Dec. 11 (Box I:B11, Reel 160)
    - 1861, Nov. 26-1863, Dec. 16 (Box I:B12, Reel 160)
    - 1864, Jan. 7-1866, Dec. 15 (Box I:B13, Reel 160)
    - 1867, Jan. 10-1868, Jan. 18 (Box I:B14 pt. 1, Reel 161)
    - 1868, Jan. 21-Dec. 29 (Box I:B14 pt. 2, Reel 161)
    - 1869, Jan. 4-1870, Dec. 27 (Box I:B15 pt. 1, Reel 161)
    - 1870, Dec. 31-1871, Dec. 29 (Box I:B15 pt. 2, Reel 162)
    - 1872, Jan. 10-1873, Apr. 28 (Box I:B16 pt. 1, Reel 162)
    - 1873, Apr. 29-Dec. 25 (Box I:B16 pt. 2, Reel 162)
    - 1874, Jan. 8-1875, Nov. 7 (Box I:B17, Reel 163)
    - 1876, Feb. 11-1877, Aug. 29 (Box I:B18 pt. 1, Reel 163)
    - 1877, Sept. 3-1878-Dec. 23 (Box I:B18 pt. 2, Reel 163)
    - 1879, Jan. 1-Oct. 3 (Box I:B19 pt. 1, Reel 164)
    - 1879, Oct. 6-1880, Dec. 29 (Box I:B19 pt. 2, Reel 164)
    - 1881, Jan. 18-Sept. 13 (Box I:B20 pt. 1, Reel 164)
    - 1881, Sept. 30-1882, Dec. 28 (Box I:B20 pt. 2, Reel 165)
    - 1883, Jan. 15-1884, May 23 (Box I:B21 pt. 1, Reel 165)
    - 1884, May 24-Dec. 30 (Box I:B21 pt. 2, Reel 166)
    - 1885 (Box I:B22 pt. 1, Reel 166)
      - Jan. 1-July 7
      - July 8-Dec. 26 (Box I:B22 pt. 2, Reel 167)
    - 1886 (Box I:B23 pt. 1, Reel 167)
      - Jan. 1-July 7 (Box I:B23 pt. 2, Reel 167)
      - July 19-Dec. 30
    - 1874, Sept. 20-1878, Sept. 8
    - 1887 (Box I:B24 pt. 1, Reel 168)
      - Jan. 8-June 27
      - June 28-Dec. 27 (Box I:B24 pt. 2, Reel 168)
    - 1888 (Box I:B25 pt. 1, Reel 169)
      - Jan. 5-May 14
      - May 16-Dec. 24 (Box I:B25 pt. 2, Reel 169)
    - 1889, Jan. 4-Dec. 27 (Box I:B26, Reel 170)
    - 1893, Apr. 24-1897, June 7 (Box I:B27 pt. 1, Reel 170)
    - 1897, July 12-1899, Sept. 19 (Box I:B27 pt. 2, Reel 170)
    - 1899, Sept. 25-1903, Mar. 23 (Box I:B28 pt. 1, Reel 171)
    - 1903, Feb. 2-1917, June 8 (Box I:B28 pt. 2, Reel 171)
    - Miscellaneous, 1840-1848 (Box I:B29, Reel 171)
    - Dispatches of Thomas Buchanan, 1839-1841 (Box I:B30, Reel 172)
    - Dispatches from Joseph Jenkins Roberts, 1840-1848 (Box I:B31, Reel 172)
    - Letters from J. N. Lewis and J. W. Lugenbeel, 1841, 1848 (Box I:B32, Reel 173)
  - C: Herndon Slaves, 1854 (Box I:C1-I:C2, Reel 173)
    Letters received by the society in response to a special circular appealing for funds to send the slaves liberated by T. D. Herndon of Virginia to Liberia.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Aug. 4-21 (Box I:C1, Reel 173)
    - Aug. 21-Dec. 2 (Box I:C2, Reel 173)
  - D: William McLain Private Letters, 1831-1850 (Box I:D1-I:D4, Reel 174-177A)
    Letters received by McLain from friends and members of his family generally concerning personal matters.
    - 1831, Oct. 27-1836, Sept. 6 (Box I:D1 pt. 1, Reel 174A)
    - 1836, Sept. 13-1837, Dec. 23 (Box I:D1 pt. 2, Reel 174B)
    - 1838, Jan. 9-1839, Nov. 6 (Box I:D2 pt. 1, Reel 174B)
    - 1839, Nov. 30-1840, Dec. 28 (Box I:D2 pt. 2, Reel 175)
    - 1841, Jan. 28-1843, Jan. 16 (Box I:D3 pt. 1, Reel 175)
    - 1843, Jan. 24-1844, Dec. 23 (Box I:D3 pt. 2, Reel 176)
    - 1848, Jan. 16-1849, Sept. 6 (Box I:D4 pt. 1, Reel 176)
    - 1849, Sept. 13-1850, Dec. 28 (Box I:D4 pt. 2, Reel 177A)
  - E: Miscellaneous, 1819-1912 (Box I:E1-I:E5, Reel 177B-181)
    Letters received. Much of the early material consists of letters from Jehudi Ashmun in Liberia concerning the conditions and problems in the colony in the 1820s.
    - 1819-1839, letters received, domestic (Box I:E1, Reel 177B)
    - 1823, letters from Liberia
    - 1829
    - 1840-1843, (2 folders)
    - 1845-1855, (4 folders)
    - Agreement between the American Colonization Society and the Republic of Liberia, 1849, Mar. 23-1856, Dec. 13
    - 1856-1859
    - 1860, “Liberated Slaves”
    - 1860-1864, (10 folders)
    - 1864-1889, (16 folders) (Box I:E2, Reel 178)
    - 1890
      - Jan.-Aug., (3 folders)
      - Nov.-Dec.
      - Sept.-Oct. (Box I:E3, Reel 179)
    - 1891
      - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
      - Apr.
      - Mar.
      - May-Dec., (8 folders)
    - 1892
      - Jan.-Feb., (4 folders)
    - Mar -Dec., (4 folders) (Box I:E4, Reel 180)
    - 1893, Jan.-Dec.
    - 1894, Jan.-July
    - Report on missionaries, 1894
    - 1894, Sept.-Oct.
    - 1895-1897, (3 folders)
    - 1899
    - 1898 (Box I:E5, Reel 181)
    - 1909, (2 folders)
    - 1910, (2 folders)
    - 1911, (3 folders)
    - 1912
    - Undated
    - 1900-1908, (3 folders)
- II: Outgoing Correspondence, 1839-1912 (Box II:1-54, Reel 182-242)
  - Domestic Letters, 1839-1912 (Box II: 1-40, Reel 182-230)
    Letters sent by society's administrative officers, chiefly the current secretary, concerning general matters.
    - Wilkeson, Samuel, and others (Box II: 1, Reel 182)
      - 1839, May 7-1840, Sept. 25
      - 1840, Sept.25-1841, Aug. 13 (Box II:2, Reel 183)
    - McLain, William, and others (Box II:3, Reel 184-185)
      - 1841, Aug. 13-1843, July 24
      - 1843, July 25-1845, Mar. 10 (Box II:4, Reel 186)
      - 1845, Mar. 10-1846, Nov. 24 (Box II:5, Reel 187)
      - 1846, Nov. 25-1848, Aug. 12 (Box II:6, Reel 188)
      - 1848, Aug. 14-1849, Nov. 16 (Box II:7, Reel 189)
      - 1849, Nov. 16-1851, Mar. 3 (Box II:8, Reel 190-191)
      - 1851, Mar. 5-1852, Mar. 26 (Box II:9, Reel 192)
      - 1852, Mar. 26-Nov. 2 (Box II:10, Reel 193)
      - 1852, Nov. 2-1853, Sept. 17 (Box II:11, Reel 194-195)
      - 1853, Sept. 19-1854, July 19 (Box II:12, Reel 196)
      - 1854, July 22-1855, May 29 (Box II:13, Reel 197-198)
      - 1855, May 29-1856, Oct. 29 (Box II:14, Reel 199-200)
      - 1856, Oct. 30-1858, July 10 (Box II:15, Reel 200-201)
      - 1858, July 13-1860, Dec. 17 (Box II:16, Reel 201-202)
      - 1860, Dec. 18-1862, Aug. 26 (Box II:17, Reel 203)
      - 1862, Aug. 27-1865, May 10 (Box II:18, Reel 204)
      - 1865, June 10-1867, Nov. 15 (Box II:19, Reel 205)
      - 1867, Nov. 15-1870, Oct. 22 (Box II:20, Reel 206-207)
      - 1870, Oct. 22-1873, Jan. 31 (Box II:21, Reel 208)
    - Coppinger, William, and others (Box II:22, Reel 209)
      - 1864, Jan.-1865, Oct. 14
      - 1865, Oct. 16-1868, Feb. 18 (Box II:23, Reel 210-211)
      - 1868, Feb. 18-1870, Apr. 14 (Box II:24, Reel 211-212)
      - 1870, Apr. 15-1872, May 31 (Box II:25, Reel 213-214)
      - 1872, June 5-1874, June 9 (Box II:26, Reel 214-215)
      - 1874, June 10-1877, June 28 (Box II:27, Reel 216-217)
      - 1877, June 30-1879, Sept. 29 (Box II:28, Reel 217-218)
      - 1879, Oct. 1-1881, June 28 (Box II:29, Reel 219)
      - 1881, June 29-1883, June 21 (Box II:30, Reel 220)
      - 1883, June 22-1885, Mar. 7 (Box II:31, Reel 221)
      - 1885, Mar. 9-1886, Dec. 11 (Box II:32, Reel 222)
      - 1886, Dec. 13-1888, Oct. 19 (Box II:33, Reel 223)
      - 1888, Oct. 22-1890, Sept. 26 (Box II:34, Reel 224)
      - 1890, Sept. 27-1892, Feb. 22 (Box II:35, Reel 225)
    - Wilson, Ormand J., and others (Box II:36, Reel 226)
      - 1892, Feb. 22-1893, June 29
      - 1893, June 26-1895, Aug. 13 (Box II:37, Reel 227)
      - 1895, Aug. 13-1898, Dec. 22 (Box II:38, Reel 228)
      - 1898, Dec. 23-1904, Nov. 29 (Box II:39, Reel 229)
      - 1904, Nov. 30-1912, Apr. 27 (Box II:40, Reel 230)
  - Ralph R. Gurley Letterbooks, 1856-1866 (Box II:41-45, Reel 231-235)
    Letters written by Gurley when he was corresponding secretary of the society.
    - 1856, Jan. 1-Sept. (Box II:41, Reel 231)
    - 1856, Sept. 2-1857, Sept. 23 (Box II:42, Reel 232)
    - 1857, Sept. 25-1859, Mar. 31 (Box II:43, Reel 233)
    - 1859, Apr. 1-1861, Jan. 23 (Box II:44, Reel 234)
    - 1861, Jan. 24-1866, Sept. 7 (Box II:45, Reel 235)
  - Joseph Tracey Letterbooks, 1856-1873 (Box II: 46-48, Reel 235-237)
    Letters of the secretary of the Massachusetts Colonization Society concerning matters involving that organization, particularly its relations with the parent society.
    - 1856, June 20-1859, May 24 (Box II: 46, Reel 235)
    - 1859, June 1-1867, May 7 (Box II:47, Reel 236)
    - 1867, May 9-1873, Aug. 20 (Box II:48, Reel 237)
  - Letters from Liberia, 1843-1874 (Box II: 49-54, Reel 238-242)
    Letters received from Liberia.
    - 1843, July 13-1852, Oct. 1 (Box II: 49, Reel 238)
    - 1850, Dec. 13-1856, June 19 (Box II:50, Reel 239)
    - 1856, July 31-1862, Mar. 7 (Box II:51, Reel 240)
    - 1862, Mar. 7-1873, Jan. 30 (Box II:52, Reel 241)
    - Sailings to Liberia and related matter, 1848-1853 (Box II:53, Reel 242)
    - From J. W. Lugenbeel, 1852-1857
    - From Ralph R. Gurley, 1858-1864 (Box II:54, Reel 242)
    - From legation of Liberia, 1865-1874
- III: General Correspondence, 1909-1965 (Box III: 1-9, Reel 243-250)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence relating chiefly to administrative matters when the activity of the society was limited and membership dwindled.
  - 1909-1918 (Box III: 1, Reel 243)
  - 1910-1939
    - A-F
    - G-S (Box III: 2, Reel 244)
    - T-Z (Box III: 3, Reel 245)
  - 1935-1941 (Box III: 4, Reel 246)
  - 1942-1948 (Box III: 5, Reel 247)
  - 1949-1954 (Box III: 6, Reel 248)
  - 1954-1956 (Box III: 7, Reel 248)
  - 1957-1960 (Box III: 8, Reel 249)
  - 1960-1963 (Box III: 9, Reel 250)
  - Financial, 1960-1965
- IV: Financial Papers, 1818-1963 (Box IV: 1-96, Reel 251-285)
  Receipts, account books, ledgers, statements, and miscellaneous papers of a purely financial nature. A small amount of correspondence concerning financial matters is included.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Accounts and receipts (Box IV: 1, Reel 251)
    - 1832-1859
    - 1850-1859 (Box IV: 2, Reel 252-253)
    - 1854-1858 (Box IV: 3, Reel 254-255)
    - 1859-1860 (Box IV: 4, Reel 256-257)
    - 1860-1864 (Box IV: 5, Reel 258-259)
    - 1850s-1865 (Box IV: 6, Reel 260-263)
    - 1860-1909 (Box IV: 7, Reel 264-265)
    - 1861-1868 (Box IV: 8, Reel 266-267)
    - 1869-1879 (Box IV: 9, Reel 268-269)
    - 1871-1874 (Box IV: 10, Reel 270-272)
    - 1874-1878 (Box IV: 11)
    - 1878-1884 (Box IV: 12)
    - 1885-1888 (Box IV: 13)
    - 1889-1899 (Box IV: 14)
    - 1895-1909 (Box IV: 15)
    - 1905-1909 (Box IV: 16)
    - 1910-1929, undated (Box IV: 17)
  - Bills of lading, 1845-1865
  - Bills and receipts
  - Financial reports
    - 1912, 1942-1948
    - 1949-1963 (Box IV: 18)
  - Insurance policies
  - Leases
  - Leases (Box IV: 19)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Notes and statements from James L. Norris, treasurer
    - 1898-1901
    - 1902-1907
  - Treasurer's vouchers and auditors' reports (Box IV: 20)
    - 1912-1917
    - 1918-1938 (Box IV: 21)
  - Miscellaneous account books and books listing donations (Box IV: 22)
  - American Security & Trust Co., correspondence and statements, 1912-1939 (Box IV: 23)
  - Finance letters, 1839-1840 (Box IV: 24, Reel 273)
  - Account books (Box IV: 25, Reel 273)
    - 1827, Mar. 10-1830, Jan. 1
    - 1830, Jan. 2-1831, Dec. 31 (Box IV: 26, Reel 273)
    - 1832, Jan. 3-1834, Apr. 24 (Box IV: 27, Reel 274)
    - 1832, Jan. 2-1840, Dec. 21 (Box IV: 28, Reel 274)
  - Accounts (Box IV: 29)
    - 1885, Oct. 7-1892, June 28
    - 1957-1963 (Box IV: 30)
  - Ledger accounts (Box IV: 31, Reel 275)
    - 1830, Jan. 2-1831, Dec. 31
    - 1833-1839 (Box IV: 32, Reel 275)
  - Ledger, 1818-1829 (Box IV: 33, Reel 275)
  - Ledger B, 1834-1837 (Box IV: 34, Reel 275)
  - Index to ledger B (Box IV: 35, Reel 275)
  - Ledger C, 1836-1842 (Box IV: 36, Reel 275)
  - Ledger D, 1842-1845 (Box IV: 37, Reel 276)
  - Ledger E, 1846-1854 (Box IV: 38, Reel 276)
  - Ledger F, 1855-1859 (Box IV: 39, Reel 276)
  - Ledger G, 1859-1876 (Box IV: 40, Reel 276)
  - Index to ledger G (Box IV: 41, Reel 276)
  - Ledgers (Box IV: 42)
    - 1898-1930
    - 1931-1963 (Box IV: 43)
  - Accounts ledger, 1907 (Box IV: 44)
  - Ledger, auxiliary society, 1820-1830 (Box IV: 45, Reel 277)
  - Journals (Box IV: 46, Reel 277)
    - 1827, Aug. 20-1830, Apr. 1
    - 1831-1832 (Box IV: 47, Reel 277)
    - 1834, Jan. 22-1840, Jan. 20 (Box IV: 48, Reel 277)
    - 1842, Jan.-1845, Dec. (Box IV: 49, Reel 277)
    - 1846, Jan.-1854, Dec. 30 (Box IV: 50, Reel 277)
    - 1850, July 1-1854, Dec. 30 (Box IV: 51, Reel 278)
    - 1855, Jan.-1859, Dec. (Box IV: 52, Reel 278)
    - 1859, Dec. -1865, Dec. (Box IV: 53, Reel 278)
    - 1866, Jan.-1875, Dec. (Box IV: 54, Reel 279)
    - 1876, Jan. 1-1877, Dec. 31 (Box IV: 55, Reel 279)
    - 1876, Jan.-1904, Feb. (Box IV: 56, Reel 279)
    - 1907 (Box IV: 57)
    - Massachusetts Auxiliary (Box IV: 58, Reel 280)
      - 1845-1849
      - 1849-1929, Sept.-1854, Apr. (Box IV: 59, Reel 280)
      - 1854, May 1-1867, Apr. 30 (Box IV: 60, Reel 280)
    - 1820-1842 (Box IV: 61, Reel 280)
    - 1898-1958 (Box IV: 62)
  - Cashbook, 1849, Jan. 9-1853, May 6 (Box IV: 63, Reel 281)
  - Treasurer's accounts (Box IV: 64, Reel 281)
    - 1847-1872
    - 1853, May 6-1857, Nov. 19 (Box IV: 65, Reel 281)
    - 1857, Nov. 26-1866, Dec. 31 (Box IV: 66, Reel 282)
    - 1867, Jan. 7-1876, Jan. 21 (Box IV: 67, Reel 282)
  - Cash accounts, 1895, Jan. 1-1911, Jan. 13 (Box IV: 68)
  - Cashbook, 1907-1963 (Box IV: 69)
  - Liberia accounts (Box IV: 70, Reel 283)
    - 1841-1842
    - 1841-1842 (Box IV: 71, Reel 283)
    - 1841-1845 (Box IV: 72, Reel 283)
    - 1841-1848 (Box IV: 73, Reel 283)
    - 1842 (Box IV: 74, Reel 283)